Guide to the Sempervirens Fund Photographs PC0205
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Sempervirens Fund Photographs
1902-2001
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Sempervirens Fund
Hill, Andrew P., 1853-1922
PC0205
15 Linear Feet 20 boxes
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research use; materials must be requested at least 48 hours in advance of intended use. Audio-visual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of the Sempervirens Fund, 2018.
Biographical / Historical
The Sempervirens Fund was originally established as the Sempervirens Club by Andrew Putnam (A.P.) Hill in 1900. California’s oldest land trust, the Sempervirens Fund’s mission is to protect and permanently preserve redwood (Sequoia sempervirens) forests, wildlife habitat, watersheds, and other important natural and scenic features of California’s Santa Cruz Mountains, and to encourage public appreciation and enjoyment of this environment.
https://sempervirens.org/
Scope and Contents
Sempervirens Fund photographic prints and negatives dating from 1902-2001. Collection includes photographic print and studio album by Andrew Putnam (A.P.) Hill.
Big Basin Redwoods State Park (Calif.); Redwoods; Forest conservation; Sempervirens Fund; Hill, Andrew P., 1853-1922
- Photographs, Accession ARCH_2018_078
  - Documentation and inventories (Box 1)
  - Big Basin Groves (Box 2, Folder 1-5)
  - Big Basin Scenery (Box 3, Folder 1-2)
  - Big Basin Standing Trees (Box 3, Folder 3-4)
  - Birds and Beasts (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Flora (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Big Basin, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Eagle Rock, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Frank Balthis, San Lorenzo River Redwoods, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Howard King (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - William K. Matthias, Aerials, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Various (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Pacific View, Craig Springs, 1975-1979 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Rancho del Oso (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Slideshow C: Forest Memorials: Dedicated Groves, 1981 Jul (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Slideshow G: Chronicles of the Redwood Era, 1981 Apr (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Slideshow I: From the Skyline to Big Basin, 1981 Apr (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Slideshow: A Walk in the Redwoods (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Slide Show Scripts (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Glass plate negatives (Box 6)
  - Glass plate negatives (Box 7)
  - Glass plate negatives (Box 8)
  - Glass plate negatives (Box 9)
  - Glass plate negatives (Box 10)
  - Glass plate negatives (Box 11)
  - Glass plate negatives (Box 12)
  - King negatives (Box 13)
  - Fulmer (Box 14)
  - H. King Negatives with Inventories (Box 15)
  - Hill Studio photograph album, F037 (Box 15)
  - Photograph of children fishing (Box 15)
  - California Legislature certificate of recognition, 2011 May 7 (Box 15)
  - Photograph of unidentified man. "Joe and Lou from Herb, Christmas 1944" on verso. (Box 15)
  - Audiovisual materials (Box 16)
  - Postcards (Box 17)
  - Antique photographs (Box 18)
  - Antique photographs (Box 19)
  - Framed photograph of Hollow Tree, Hollow Tree Camp, Big Basin, taken by A.P. Hill, 1902 Jul (Box 20)
  - Hollow Tree caption/citation (Box 20)